Text data, especially from online sources,
文本数据 特别是来自网络来源的文本数据
is almost never clean.
几乎不可能是整洁的
Let's look at the Udacity course catalog as an example.
我们以优达学城的课程目录作为示例
Say you want to extract the title and description of each course or Nanodegree.
假如你想提取每个课程或纳米学位的标题和描述
Sounds simple, right?
听起来很简单 对吧
Let's jump into Python and give it a shot.
我们用 Python 试一下
You can follow along by downloading and launching the text processing notebook.
可以下载并启动用于处理文本的 notebook
We can fetch the web page like any other online resource using the requests library.
像任何其它在线资源一样 可以使用 request 库来获取网页
It looks like we got back the entire HTML source.
看起来得到了全部 HTML 源代码
This is what the browser needs to render the web page.
这正是浏览器显示网页所需的东西
But most of this is useless for our purposes.
但是大多数对我们来说没用
We need a way to extract all the plain text as visible on the website.
我们需要提取网站上可见的所有纯文本
How about using regular expressions?
使用正则表达式怎么样？
Let's define a pattern to match
我们定义一个模式
all HTML tags and remove them by replacing with a blank string.
匹配所有 HTML 标签 并用空字符串替换它们 将其清除
Okay, that did something.
这个方法有点用
We can see that the page title has been extracted successfully,
可以看到 网页标题已经成功提取
but there is a lot of JavaScript and a number of other items that we don't need.
但是仍然有很多不需要的 JavaScript 和其它项目
In fact, this regular expression somehow didn't match some tags.
实际上 这种正则表达式在某种程度上没有区配一些标签
Maybe they were nested inside other tags.
它们可能嵌套在其它标签内
Maybe we need to account for tags spread across lines.
我们可能需要找出分布在行之间的标签
Anyway, this doesn't seem like the best approach for this job.
总之 这好像不是最好的方法
What we really need is a way to parse the HTML,
我们真正需要的是对 HTML 进行解析
just like a web browser,
就像网页浏览器
and pull out the relevant elements.
然后提取相关元素
Introducing BeautifulSoup.
我们现在介绍 Beautiful Soup
It's a nice Python library meant to do exactly that.
这是一个很有效的 Python 库 专用于这个用途
You just pass in the raw web page text which in this case
可以传入原始网页文本（在该示例中 包含 HTML）
contains HTML to create a soup object,
以创建 soup 对象
and then you can extract the plain text,
用 简单的get-text 方法
leaving behind any HTML tags using a symbol called to the get-text method.
提取HTML标签后的纯文本
This takes care of nested tags,
这种方法也针对嵌套标签
tags that are broken across lines,
跨行的标签
and a multitude of other edge cases that make HTML parsing a pain.
以及增加 HTML 解析难度的多种其它极端情况
It also forgives some small errors in HTML just like browsers,
像浏览器一样 它还会忽略HTML 中的一些小错误
making it more robust. Let's see.
使其更稳健 我们看一下
That's better.
现在好多了
I don't see any HTML tags,
看不到任何 HTML 标签
but there are still a bunch of JavaScript and a lot of spaces.
但是仍然有很多 JavaScript 和空格
What else can we do? Let's take a look at how the HTML source is structured.
我们还能怎么做？ 我们看一下 HTML 源代码的结构
The easiest way to do this is to right click on an element of your choice,
最简单的方法是 随便右击一个元素
here, this course title,
例如这个课程标题
and choose Inspect or View Page Source.
然后选择“检查元素” 或者 “查看网页来源”
Now look at where the title is placed and what is
现在看一下标题在什么位置
the most distinct way of finding it in the HTML documentary.
要在 HTML 文件中找到这个标题 最好的方法是什么？
Here, we have a parent div with a class of course summary card.
这里有一个父块 包含一个“课程摘要卡”类
That sounds promising. Let's use it.
好像有用 我们用一下
BeautifulSoup is actually very powerful.
Beautiful Soup 实际非常强大
It enables you to walk the tree or dorm in many different ways.
它能让你通过多种不同方法对 DOM 树进行通览
Here we are asking the library to find all divs with a class of course summary card.
我们现在用该库找到含有“课程摘要卡”类的所有块
The result returned is a list of all such divs in the document.
返回的结果是文件中所有这种块的列表
Let's store this in a variable and look at one of the divs.
我们把它存储在变量中 看其中一个块
Okay. Scrolling through this,
好了 滚动页面
I see that the title is stored in this a-tag which is contained in this H3 tag.
我发现标题存储在这个 a 标签中 而 a 标签包含在这个 H3 标签中
How do we extract this title?
如何提取这个标题？
One way to get to it is using a CSS selector.
一种方法是使用 CSS 选择器
And now we can fetch the plain text content just like we did before.
现在可以像之前一样 找到纯文本内容
Great. One last thing.
很好 还有最后一步
Let's strip out the extra whitespace from both ends. There you go.
删除两端的多余空格 好了
Now, let's look back at the HTML to see how we
现在再看 HTML 看看如何
can grab the description text. There it is.
提取描述文本 就是这个
It's a div with an attribute called data-course-short-summary,
这个块包含名为 “data-course-short-summary” 的属性
but no value or any other attribute.
但是不含值和任何其它属性
Again, there is a way to select such tags using CSS.
这是一种通过 CSS 选择这种标签的方法
Specify the tag name, here, div,
指定标签名 这里是 div
followed by the attribute name in square brackets. Looks good.
后面用方括号写上属性名称 很好
Let's extract the text and clean it up.
现在提取文本 并进行清洗
All right. We can now repeat this over all course summaries.
好了 现在可以对所有课程摘要重复这个过程
To do this, we can use a simple for loop.
为此 可以使用简单的 for 循环
Looks spot on to me.
我认为非常准确
Let's store this data so we can use it later.
存储这个数据 便于以后使用
Here, we are simply keeping the data in a list called courses.
这里 我们只是简单地将数据保存在名为“课程”的列表中
What we did just now is called scraping a web page.
刚才的过程叫做网页抓取
Although it sounds a little violent,
虽然听起来有点暴力
trust me, it's not.
相信我 并不是
In fact, scraping is very common.
实际上网页抓取非常常见
Google News is a prime example.
Google News 就是一个很好的例子
It pulls out the title and first sentence or two from news articles and displays them.
它从新闻文章中提取标题和开头的一两个句子 将其显示出来
Google probably uses a combination of rules and
Google 可能是利用多种规则和
machine learning to identify what portion of
机器学习 识别 HTML 的哪个部分
the HTML contains the title and
包含文章文本的标题和开头
the beginning of the article text that it can use as a preview.
将其作为预览
It works great most of the time,
大多数情况下会成功
but sometimes, it does fail.
但有时会失败
Here, for this article on quantum entanglement,
这篇有关量子纠缠的文章
the preview doesn't seem to match the title at all.
其预览好像与标题毫不相干
It looks more like a caption for this image.
更像是这个图片的说明
What likely happened is that the caption was the first piece of text on
可能因为图片说明是网页文本的第一部分
the web page and Google's algorithm picked that up as if it was part of the main article.
Google 的算法将其作为文章主体的一部分进行提取
This just goes to show how seemingly routine tasks and
这说明 看似常规的任务和
text processing are still not solved all the way.
文本处理问题 仍然不能被完美解决
Okay, let's look back at what we just achieved.
我们再看一下刚才的成果
We started by fetching a single web page,
我们得到了一个网页
the Udacity course catalog.
优达学城的课程目录
Then we tried a couple of methods to remove HTML tags.
然后尝试了几种方法 清除 HTML 标签
We finally settled on using BeautifulSoup to parse the entire HTML source,
最后用 BeautifulSoup 对整个 HTML 源代码进行解析
find all course summaries,
找到所有课程摘要
and extract the title and description for each course.
提取每个课程的标题和描述
And then we saved them all in a list.
然后全部保存到一个列表
Depending on what you're planning to do next,
根据后续计划
you may continue to treat these chunks as part of
可以将这些块作为一个文档的一部分
a single document or consider each to be a separate document.
或者将每个块作为单独的文档
The latter is useful,
如果你想将相关课程归类
for instance, if you want to group related courses.
第二种方式更好
The problem then reduces to document clustering.
剩下的问题便是文档聚类